<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" standalone="no"?>
<operatorHelp lang="en_EN">
    <!--  This is an example how to specify the description of operators and the translation of it's key identifier
    to names. --> 

   <operator>
      <name>SingleTextInput</name>
      <synopsis>Generates word vectors from a single text.</synopsis>
      <help />
   </operator>
   <operator>
      <name>TextObjectWriter</name>
      <synopsis>Writes a textobject into a file.</synopsis>
      <help>This operator writes a given textObject into a file. It might be specified if an existing file with the same name should be overwritten.</help>
   </operator>

   <operator>
      <name>News Aligner</name>
      <synopsis>Generates a time association between the news and the stock prices.</synopsis>
      <help>This operator generates an association between a new and a set of stock prices, the result is recorded on the table alignement. These records consists of the news_id and the label assigned to this news, given a time window that is supposed to afect a set of prices sorted by time (aka time series) of a specified asset.
      	<![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
      	<![CDATA[<b>]]>References<![CDATA[</b><br>]]>
      	[1] Beckmann, M., Ebecken, N.F.F., De Lima, B.S.L.P, 2015, Stock Price Change Prediction Using News Text Mining. Unpublished.
      	<![CDATA[<br>]]>
      	[2] Lavrenko, V., Et. Al, 2000, Mining of Concurrent Text and Time Series. In: Proceedings 6th ACM SIGKDD Int. Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining. Boston 2000, pp. 37-44.
      	<![CDATA[<br>]]>
      	</help>
   </operator>


   <operator>
      <name>KNN Undersampling</name>
      <synopsis>Performs a selective database cleaning and class balancing using KNN</synopsis>
      <help>Performs a selective cleaning dataset, given a specified label using a KNN approach. This selective cleaning is also known as dataset balancing or undersampling.
      	<![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
      	<![CDATA[<b>]]>References<![CDATA[</b><br>]]>
      	[1] Beckmann, M., Ebecken, N.F.F., De Lima, B.S.L.P, 2015, A KNN Undersampling Approach for Data Balancing. Unpublished.
      	<![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
      	</help>
   </operator>



   <operator>
      <name>KNN Undersampling no Label</name>
      <synopsis>This is similar to KNN Undersampling, but for the test set, it is assumed there's no label available. This operator is useful to validate prediction, where NO LABEL DATA in the future can leak, only training data will be availabe.</synopsis>
      <help>Performs a selective cleaning dataset, given a specified label using a KNN approach. This selective cleaning is also known as dataset balancing or undersampling.
      	<![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
      	<![CDATA[<b>]]>References<![CDATA[</b><br>]]>
      	[1] Beckmann, M., Ebecken, N.F.F., De Lima, B.S.L.P, 2015, A KNN Undersampling Approach for Data Balancing. Unpublished.
      	<![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
      	</help>
   </operator>


   <operator>
      <name>Generate N-Gram Word List</name>
      <synopsis>Generates a N-GRAM wordlist file</synopsis>
      <help>Reads the text attribute existing in the input exampleset and generates a text file with a list of word combinations (N-GRAMS) existing in the input.
      	<![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
      	
      	<![CDATA[<b>]]>References<![CDATA[</b><br>]]>
      	<![CDATA[<br>]]>
      	</help>
   </operator>



   <operator>
      <name>Performance (Weka)</name>
      <synopsis>Calculates performance measures with Weka engine</synopsis>
      <help>This operator performs Weka machine learning measure calculations in order to evaluate the predictive process, given a exampleset with predicted results.
      	 The output will be a ExampleSet with the calculation for requested measures, and a record in the experiment description table.
      	 Recomended after this to use the Write Database Operator to write the results in a table.
      	<![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
      	
      	<![CDATA[<b>]]>References<![CDATA[</b><br>]]>
      	[1] Fawcett, T. (2004) ROC Graphs: Notes and Practical Considerations for Researchers – HP Laboratories.
      	<![CDATA[<br>]]>
      	[2] Ian H. W., Frank E. (2005) Data Mining: Practical machine learning tools and techniques, 2nd Edition, Morgan Kaufmann, San Francisco.
      	<![CDATA[<br>]]>
      	</help>
   </operator>



   <operator>
      <name>Read Macros From Data</name>
      <synopsis>Create macros from ExampleSet</synopsis>
      <help>This operator creates several macros based on an input ExampleSet.</help>
   </operator>



   <operator>
      <name>Random Undersampling</name>
      <synopsis>Random removal of examples from an ExampleSet given a selected label.</synopsis>
      <help>This operator performs a removal of examples of a specified label from a ExampleSet in order 
      	to balance the number of examples between the classes.
      	<![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
      	
      	<![CDATA[<b>]]>References<![CDATA[</b><br>]]>
      	[1] Beckmann, M., Ebecken, N.F.F., De Lima, B.S.L.P, 2015, A KNN Undersampling Approach for Data Balancing. Unpublished.
      	<![CDATA[<br>]]>
      	</help>
   </operator>



   <operator>
      <name>Performance To ExampleSet</name>
      <synopsis>Transforms a Rapidminer performance into an ExampleSet</synopsis>
      <help>This operator transforms a performance input into an ExampleSet</help>
   </operator>


   <operator>
      <name>Remove words not in Dictionary</name>
      <synopsis>Performs the removal of words if they are not present in a word list.</synopsis>
      <help>This operator removes words from a specified text attribute from a ExampleSet, if these words are not present in a word list.
      	<![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
      	
      	<![CDATA[<b>]]>References<![CDATA[</b><br>]]>
		[1] Beckmann, M., Ebecken, N.F.F., De Lima, B.S.L.P, 2015, Stock Price Change Prediction Using News Text Mining. Unpublished.
      	<![CDATA[<br>]]>
      	</help>
   </operator>

   <operator>
      <name>Custom Content Updater</name>
      <synopsis>Gets the content of an url obtained from a RSS </synopsis>
      <help>This operator downloads the content of a url stored previously and stores it on the content column of table rss. This url is obtained from a RSS in the web crawler processing.
      	<![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
      	
      	<![CDATA[<b>]]>References<![CDATA[</b><br>]]>

      	<![CDATA[<br>]]>
      	</help>
   </operator>



   <operator>
      <name>Text Summarization</name>
      <synopsis>Performs text summarization.</synopsis>
      <help>This operator makes text summarization on a specified text attribute from a ExampleSet.
      	<![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
      	
      	<![CDATA[<b>]]>References<![CDATA[</b><br>]]>
		[1] Kolcz, A., Prabakarmurthi, V., Kalita, J., 2000, Summarization as feature selection for text categorization, In Proc. CIKM, pp. 365-370. ACM Press. 

      	<![CDATA[<br>]]>
      	</help>
   </operator>

   <operator>
      <name>Simple Strategy Simulator</name>
      <synopsis>Operates an investment simulator, using a simple strategy of investment proposed in [2], given the learner outcome and a marketdata feeding</synopsis>
      <help>This operator is under construction.
      	<![CDATA[<p></p>]]>
      	
      	<![CDATA[<b>]]>References<![CDATA[</b><br>]]>
      	[1] Beckmann, M., Ebecken, N.F.F., De Lima, B.S.L.P, 2015, Stock Price Change Prediction Using News Text Mining. Unpublished.
      	<![CDATA[<br>]]>
      	[2] Lavrenko, V., Et. Al, 2000, Mining of Concurrent Text and Time Series. In: Proceedings 6th ACM SIGKDD Int. Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining. Boston 2000, pp. 37-44.
      	<![CDATA[<br>]]>
      	</help>
   </operator>




    This is how group ids are translated:
    
    
   <group>
      <key>text_processing</key>
      <name>Text Processing</name>
   </group>

   

</operatorHelp>